<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
    <name>!Sewing machine</name>
    <directory>sewing machine</directory>
    <id>2145452717</id>
    <description>[h1]Repentance update is coming slowly ![/h1]

[h2]Repentance Update 0.3 : [/h2]

[list]
[*]Upgrade Blood Oath : [Super] Spawn red creep. The creep deal 0.2 * the amount of half heart removed. [Ultra] When it stab, it spawns random red hearts.
[*]Upgrade Pascal Candle : [Super] When the player takes damages, Paschal Candle spread flames around it. The amount of flames depends on the size of the flame's candle. [Ultra] Taking damage only reduces the flame by one room amount.
[*]Upgrade Cube Baby : [Super] Gain a freezing aura. Enemies which stay for too long in the aura will take damage until they are completely frozen. [Ultra] Spawn creep when moved around. The more is goes fast, the more it spawns creep.
[*]Upgrade Bot Fly : [Super] Range up. Shot Speed up. Increase tear size. [Ultra] Boosts stats. Gain piercing tears
[*]Upgrade Boiled Baby : [Super] Increase the amount of tears it burst. [Ultra] Fire tears in the directions the player is firing.
[*]Upgrade Freezer Baby : [Super] Damage Up. Range Up. Increase the chance to freeze enemies. [Ultra] Enemies it kills explodes into ice tears
[*]Upgrade Lil Dumpy : [Super] Attract close bullets. When it farts, fire  tears in different directions. [Ultra] While it moves, spawn static tears. Those tears have a chance to apply Poison, Charm or Confusion
[*]Rework Sissy Longlegs : Fix spider spawn. Spawned spiders can apply a charm effect
[*]Change mod name from &quot;Sewing Machine&quot; to &quot;!Sewing Machine&quot;
[/list]

[h2]Repentance Update 0.2 : [/h2]

[list]
[*]Rework Isaac's Heart : [Super] Move closer to the player when the player isn't firing. Decreased charge time. [Ultra] When fully charged, if an enemy or projectile gets too close it automatically activates it's fully charged effect#When this activates, it will go on a breif cooldown before being able to charge again
[*]Fix the cards/runes sprite issue
[*]Fix Dead Cat
[*]Fix King Baby
[*]Fix issues
[/list]


[h2]Repentance Update 0.1 : [/h2]

[list]
[*]Rework Brother Bobby
[*]Rework Sister Maggy
[*]Rebalance Robo Baby
[*]Rework Depression : [Super] Block always shots. [Ultra] : Tears bounce and produce more creep. Better creep)
[*]Rebalance Seraphim : (Nerf) Less chance to fire holy tears
[*]Fix Buddy in a Box : Can now use tears from repentance
[*]Rework Rainbow Baby : Tears up (less) and Damage up
[*]Rework Little Steven : Better range up. Now have a slighter shot speed down
[*]Rebalance Headless Baby : Buff
[*]Fix Mongo Baby : Fix lot of issues. Better copy familiars
[*]Fix Papa Fly
[*]Rebalance Juicy Sack : (Buff) Now fire some egg tears even in Super. Fire more egg tears in Ultra
[*]Rework Holy Water : Have been completely changed in Repentance. Spawn small puddle of creep when thrown. Gain piercing + do not break always on hit
[*]Rework The Relic : Change chances to spawn soul hearts. Can spawn eternal heart (small chance on Ultra). Rebalance chances. Can heal the player only on Ultra
[*]Rebalance Peeper : Buff
[*]Fix Leech
[*]Rebalance Cain's Other Eye : (Nerf)  Reduce amount of tears for Ultra Cain's Other Eye (From 4 to 3)
[*]Rebalance Rib familiars
[/list]


[h1]Make your familiars stronger ![/h1]


The [b]Sewing Machine[/b] is a brand new machine which allow you to [b]upgrade your familiars[/b] during a run !

63 familiars are for now upgradable !
For more info about all those upgrades, check this link : 

https://www.reddit.com/r/themoddingofisaac/comments/gwfffs/sewing_machine_mod_upgradable_familiars/

This mod include also new items and new trinkets related to the Sewing Machine.

This mod is NOT compatible with True-Coop !

--------------------------------

The sewing machine act like a slot machine. When interacting with the machine you will [b]add a random familiar[/b] in the machine. Interacting a second time with the machine will allow you to retrieve the familiar with a special upgrade. [b]Upgrades have a cost[/b], it can be a soul heart, or coins. When a familiar is in the machine, you can retrieve it when bombing the machine.
Sewing machine can be found in [b]bedrooms[/b], [b]shops[/b] or [b]arcade rooms[/b].
Familiars can be upgradable twice. A crown icon indicate their level.

[b]Sewing Box[/b] / Active Item
&quot;Temporary super familiar&quot;
Upgrade all you familiars for one room

[b]Doll's Tainted Head[/b] / Passive
&quot;???&quot;
Every familiars will be SUPER. With Doll's Pure Body every familiars will be ULTRA

[b]Doll's Pure Body[/b] / Passive
&quot;???&quot;
Every familiars will be SUPER. With Doll's Tainted Body every familiars will be ULTRA

[b]Thimble[/b] / Trinket
&quot;Safety Crowns&quot;
Reroll familiars crowns when getting hit

[b]Cracked Thimble[/b] / Trinket
&quot;Cursed crowns ?&quot;
Have a 50% chance to reduce the cost for upgrades to half the normal price

[b]Lost Button[/b] / Trinket
&quot;More sewing machines !&quot;
100% chance to spawn Sewing machine in Shops for next floors

[b]Contrasted Button[/b] / Trinket
&quot;Unexpected machine&quot;
50% chance to find a sewing machine in angel rooms or devil rooms

[b]Pin Cushion[/b] / Trinket
&quot;Choose the good one&quot;
Interacting with the machine gives the familiar back

--------------------------------

[h1]Modded familiars[/h1]
[b]Some modded familiars can work with the machine, including : [/b]
[url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=1991915308]Lost And Forgotten[/url]
[url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=1925867065]IPECAC Community Mod[/url]
[url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=840727122]Marshmallow[/url]

[h3]To make you own familiar upgradable :[/h3]
https://github.com/valentinLampriere/Isaac_Sewing-Machine/wiki

--------------------------------

Please let me know if you encounter bugs !

Some familiars aren't upgradable now.
This mod will be updated and will make more and more familiars available !

[b]Share your ideas[/b] in the comments or contact me if you have new ideas for familiars upgrades !

--------------------------------

Thanks to the Modding community for their help during the developement process

Special Thanks to
- [url=https://steamcommunity.com/profiles/76561198241259420/myworkshopfiles/]Foks[/url] for trinket sprites, ann's sprites and his support from the beginning of the mod
- [url=https://steamcommunity.com/profiles/76561198367241059/myworkshopfiles/]SupremeElf[/url] for the &quot;Sewing Box&quot; sprite, the code he made (mainly the EID compatibility) and his support 
- [url=https://steamcommunity.com/id/PixelPlz/myworkshopfiles/]PixelPlz[/url] for the awesome Sewing Machine sprite he made and the Angelic Sewing machine
- [url=https://steamcommunity.com/id/ciirulean/myworkshopfiles/]Ciirulean[/url] for the evil Sewing Machine sprite
- [url=https://steamcommunity.com/profiles/76561198118097787/myworkshopfiles/]Sentinel[/url] for all his help and advices
- [url=https://steamcommunity.com/profiles/76561198394602416/myworkshopfiles/]Spore64[/url] for nice cards sprites

--------------------------------

Mod made my [url=https://steamcommunity.com/profiles/76561198831532101/]@siraxtas[/url]
Discord : valentinL#3711

Now on Discord : https://discord.gg/56HzHdAKKG</description>
    <version>1.19</version>
    <visibility>Public</visibility>
    <tag id="Lua"/>
    <tag id="Items"/>
    <tag id="Active Items"/>
    <tag id="Trinkets"/>
    <tag id="Cards"/>
    <tag id="Pickups"/>
    <tag id="Familiars"/>
    <tag id="Tweaks"/>
</metadata>
