<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
    <name>Sewing machine</name>
    <directory>sewing machine</directory>
    <id>2145452717</id>
    <description>[h1]Make your familiars stronger ![/h1]

The [b]Sewing Machine[/b] is a brand new machine which allow you to [b]upgrade your familiars[/b] during a run !

More than 44 familiars are for now upgradable.
For more info about all those upgrades, check this link : 
https://www.reddit.com/r/themoddingofisaac/comments/gwfffs/sewing_machine_mod_upgradable_familiars/

This mod include also a new item and three new trinkets related to the Sewing Machine.

This mod is NOT compatible with True-Coop !

--------------------------------

The sewing machine act like a slot machine. When interacting with the machine you will [b]add a random familiar[/b] in the machine. Interacting a second time with the machine will allow you to retrieve the familiar with a special upgrade. [b]Upgrades have a cost[/b], it can be a soul heart, or coins. When a familiar is in the machine, you can retrieve it when bombing the machine.
Sewing machine can be found in [b]bedrooms[/b], [b]shops[/b] or [b]arcade rooms[/b].
Familiars can be upgradable twice. A crown icon indicate their level.

[b]Sewing Box[/b] / Active Item
&quot;Temporary super familiar&quot;
Upgrade all you familiars for one room

[b]Thimble[/b] / Trinket
&quot;Safety Crowns&quot;
Have a 50% chance to reduce the cost for upgrades to half the normal price

[b]Lost Button[/b] / Trinket
&quot;More sewing machines !&quot;
100% chance to spawn Sewing machine in Shops for next floors

[b]Pin Cushion[/b] / Trinket
&quot;Choose the good one&quot;
When player can't afford the upgrade of the familiar in a machine, interacting with the machine gives the familiar back

--------------------------------

Please let me know if you encounter bugs !

Some familiars aren't upgradable now.
This mod will be updated and will make more and more familiars available !

[b]Share your ideas[/b] in the comments or contact me if you have new ideas for familiars upgrades !

--------------------------------

Thank to the Modding community for there help during the developement process

Special Thanks to
- [url=https://steamcommunity.com/profiles/76561198241259420/myworkshopfiles/?appid=250900]Foks[/url] for trinket sprites and his support from the beginning of the mod
- [url=https://steamcommunity.com/profiles/76561198367241059/myworkshopfiles/?appid=250900]SupremeElf[/url] for the &quot;Sewing Box&quot; sprite, the code he made (mainly the EID compatibility) and his support 
- [url=https://steamcommunity.com/id/PixelPlz/myworkshopfiles/?appid=250900]PixelPlz[/url] for the awesome Sewing Machine sprite he made
- [url=https://steamcommunity.com/profiles/76561198118097787/myworkshopfiles/?appid=250900]Sentinel[/url] for all his help and advices

--------------------------------

Mod made my [url=https://steamcommunity.com/profiles/76561198831532101/]@siraxtas[/url]
Discord : valentinL#3711</description>
    <version>1.8</version>
    <visibility>Public</visibility>
    <tag id="Lua"/>
    <tag id="Active Items"/>
    <tag id="Trinkets"/>
    <tag id="Familiars"/>
</metadata>
